well I have the distinct honor and
privilege of IND inducting my mentor and
my hero for D po into the international
Hall of Fame his work in
internationalizing Jones day is actually
what brought me to Cleveland in
1990 at that time I was working in a law
firm in New York City but given that I
was born in Rochester New York I was
looking to move to a Midwestern City
where I could work on International
transactions and in 1990 it was Jones
day I mean that was it uh it had an
international footprint with offices in
across the United States but also in
Europe and Asia so I mean there really
was no other place other than Jones day
and that's what brought me to Cleveland
and and that footprint that
International footprint was as a result
of vision and Leadership skills of D PR
here he took I might add that he took
that action in spite of the fact that if
there had been a vote of the partnership
back then what we see as a brilliant
move would have probably suffered
overwhelming feat so he really was a
Visionary and Dick's work in
internationalizing Cleveland is not
limited to Jones Dave when When you
mention any Civic institutions such as
the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame
Progressive Field University Hospital
Cleveland Institute of Music Gordon
Square Arts District City Club of
Cleveland Cas Western Reserve University
Cleveland Foundation University of aan
the Red Cross the Greater Cleveland
partnership and I'm sure I've left a
number of organizations off the list
what you will find is that the reason
each of them is around and prospering
and has made Cleveland an international
Hub is because of the work of big
Po and but occasions like today are also
time to reflect on what makes a person
such as dick so
successful uh in the 25 years I have
known dick I've been able to discern a
number of them first as Bishop pill
mentioned success does not come from a
single person it inevitably involves
marshalling the efforts of a team and
with dick that starts with his wife Pat
Cole who's out in the audience who
helped him raise an illustrious family
and quietly counseled him and grounded
him Pat would you please stand and be
recognized
few people know Pat has you know worked
tirelessly in the community she uh
tutors uh children in the que public
school she's been working with Welcome
Wagon Le just quietly and tily helping
and obviously keeping the PO family uh
you
prospering but big success was not just
working with his family when I
interviewed back in
1990 the staff member who led me to my
different interview
told me with reverence that Mr Po knows
the name of every employee and she was
serious and he does and I remember that
when Dick came back to Jones Day after a
short stin at dick Eon he told me that
what made him extremely happy to be back
at Jones Day was seeing that so much of
the staff that had supported the firm
when he was there was still at the firm
and he really is a person who recognizes
all the efforts of others who work with
him dick is a hard and tireless worker I
remember calling dick one time at 6:00
in the morning hoping to leave him a
message and of course di picked up the
phone and you know was there uh
similarly you see him at 9 or 10 p.m.
leaving the Jones Day garage so hard
work is part of his secret I guess also
um dick May project the hard edge of ta
term business person but I've come to
learn that he's an extremely
compassionate person who selflessly goes
out of his way to assist people from all
walks of life Deborah easy of the
deaconness foundation and whose Bo dick
served told me that dick is really a
softy at heart after interviewing
potential beneficiary organizations he
would always empathize with the missions
of those seeking funds from the Deacon's
foundation and often times would
convince his fellow board members to
support projects that might otherwise
have fallen by by the
wayside one of the most important things
about dick is that he's a person with
great humility he will not tell you
directly what done and it's only in
passing that one can learn about his
accomplishments uh as you may have
remember I mentioned that he was
instrumental in getting the Rock and
Roll Hall of Fame built in this city but
dick won't tell you that and how did I
find out well I was reading in the 1990s
that dick at that time was a miror
election
had endorsed Mary Rose Oar for mayor of
Cleveland and I went to dick and I said
you're dedicated not have died in the W
Republican what are you doing supporting
congresswoman Mary Rose Oar who was in
the uh in the audience and he told me
well you know we were working on getting
the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame built and
one of the major problems was that the
Rock and Roll Hall of Fame was going to
be located on what was a mar marittime
navigation water water and so dick went
to Congressman Oar along with other some
other folks and they got a bill and
basically declared the area the site
where the Rock Hall f is not to be a
navigation Waterway and Di told me she
can get things done and that's why I
have to support Mary
[Music]
Ro so others who would have who have
accomplished what dick have accomplished
would not be shy in letting folks know
what they have done but dick is the
first one to give credits to others when
you work in teams and that's why
Cleveland needs and that's why I'm so
proud to induct dick Po in the
international Hall of
Fame